CHARLES VERLEYEN



Ph.: +32497201660 | E-mail: charles.xavier.verleyen@gmail.com | GitHub: Charles1104 | Birth date: 11/04/1988

OBJECTIVE

Data Scientist seeking to work with an international data-oriented company where I will be able to put into practice my mix of soft and hard skills acquired through ten years of education and experience in different countries and sectors.

WORK EXPERIENCE

• Data Scientist Aug 2017 – Nov 2017

Data Science Retreat (Berlin, Germany)

• Strategic Sourcing Manager

Jul 2015 - Feb 2017

Feb 2015 - Jul 2015

CTA Group (Antwerp, Belgium)

- Management of the chemical consignment contracts for three gold mines in West Africa.
- o Developer of Business analytics reports using VBA in Excel
- Project Manager

Cimko (Kinshasa, Democratic Republic of Congo)

o Project management coordinator with all the departments, daily reporting to the GM and recruitments.

• Procurement Manager

Jan 2014 - Jan 2015

Kempinski Hotel Fleuve Congo (Kinshasa, Democratic Republic of Congo)

o Responsible for all the purchases of the hotel. Managed a team of eight persons.

Supplier Quality Engineer

Dec 2012 – Dec 2013

General Electric (San Luis Potosí, Mexico)

o Responsible for the procurement of electronic commodities from 30 suppliers.

EDUCATION & PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

| • | MOOCs in data science – details on my personal website (www.charlesverleyen.me) | Jul 2017 - Dec 2017 |
|---|--|---------------------|
| • | Bootcamp in Web development – Devleague (Hawaii) | Mar 2017 - Jun 2017 |
| • | Msc in Business engineering - major in Supply Chain Management (cum laude) | Sep 2009 - Jun 2012 |
| | Louvain School of Management, Belgium and National University of Singapore | |
| • | Bsc in Business Engineering (cum laude) | Sep 2006 - Jun 2009 |
| | Université Catholique de Louvain, Belgium | |

LANGUAGES AND COMPUTER SKILLS

- Human Languages: French (native), English (fluent), Spanish (fluent), Dutch (intermediate)
- Data Science skills: Python (Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Scikit), TensorFlow, Keras, Hadoop, Spark, AWS
- Front-end and Back-end skills: Javascript (intermediate; knowledge of Angular and React), NodeJS (intermediate), HTML (intermediate), CSS (intermediate). PostgreSQL (proficient) and Sequelize (proficient).
- **Software Skills:** Microsoft office suite (VBA programmer), Microsoft Dynamic Nav 2013 & Jet reports, SAP (modules MM and PP), SAS (Certified Base Programmer for SAS 9), AnyLogic and Adobe suite.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- **APICS CPIM certificate** (5 modules achived). Obtained in September 2012.
- Vice President of a renowned Junior Enterprise (LSM Conseil www.lsmconseil.com) from 2008 until 2010.
- Volunteer in a South African camp provided care to the animals (summer 2004).
- Sports enthusiast with active participation in Tennis and Swimming; Amateur of Horse Riding.
- Holder of "PADI Open Water Diver Certificate" and "PADI Advanced Open Water Certificate".